Burwell-Glenny Family Papers, 1824-1955 (bulk 1824-1891)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Burwell-Glenny Family Papers
1824 - 1955
9 boxes, 4.5 linear ft.
Burwell-Glenny Family
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Personal and professional papers from the Burwell-Glenny Family, who worked in Buffalo in the 18th and 19th centuries.
The manuscripts of the Medical Society of the County of Erie, Mss. C71-2, include several files of materials of interest to anyone using the Burwell-Glenny collection.
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1824-1891, subseries A-J as follows: A. Bryant and Ann Clark Burwell, 1824-1856; B. Dudley Burwell, 1829-1856; c. Theodotus Burwell, 1825-1891; D. Stephen Clark, 1832-1834; E. John W. Clark, 1831-1870; F. George N. Burwell, 1828-1887; G. William H. and Esther Ann Burwell Glenny, 1834-1891; H. William H. Glenny, Jr., 1853-1883; I. Bryant B. and John C. Glenny, 1866-1868; J. Miscellaneous, 1835-1868. II. Legal and miscellaneous papers, 1826-1889. III. Bryant Burwell diaries, 1826-1889. IV. Genealogy, ca. 1951-1955.
Donor: Cornell University Libraries (donated to Cornell by Robert Stevens), Edwin A. Sy and Bryant Glenny.
Accruals are not expected to this collection.
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
William H. Glenny (1818-1882) was born in Northern Ireland and came to Buffalo in 1836. At a young age he worked as a clerk in the bookstore of A.W. Wilgus. In 1840 Glenny founded a small crockery store. Four years later he married Esther Ann, the daughter of Dr. Bryant Burwell and sister of Dr. George N. Burwell and Anna C. Rathbone. In 1877 Glenny erected the block of 251-257 Main Street, known as "Glenny Block." In 1856 he became one of the incorporators of the M & T Bank and was also a trustee of the Erie County Savings Bank. Glenny was a trustee of the First Presbyterian Church and associated with the organization of the Buffalo, New York and Philadelphia Railroad Company.
Bryant Burwell (1796-1861) was born in Russia, Herkimer County, N.Y. Burwell studied medicine with Professor Willoughby in Newport, Herkimer County. In 1817 he married Anna Clark of Newport, N.Y. and had three children, George N. Burwell, Esther A. Glenny and Anna C. Rathbone. In 1820 he was admitted into the Herkimer County Medical Society and three years later graduated from Fairfield Medical College before studying in Philadelphia in 1826-1827. In 1824 Burwell formed a partnership with Dr. Cyrenius Chapin in Buffalo, where Burwell moved to, and continued to practice until his death.
George N. Burwell (1819-1891) was the son of Bryant Burwell. He was born in Herkimer County, N.Y. in 1819. Like his father, he too received medical training in the city of Philadelphia. He served as attending physician at the Buffalo Hospital of the Sisters Charity for 30 years and was a consulting surgeon at Buffalo General Hospital. He was admitted to the Society in 1844, and died in 1891.
John Whipple Clark (1799-1872) was born in the Village of Newport, Herkimer County, N.Y. His parents were Stephen Clark and Esther Whipple, who were originally from Rhode Island. In 1822 Clark graduated from Fairfield Medical College and a year later moved to Buffalo. Clark became the partner of Dr. Cyrenius Chapin after arriving to Buffalo and gave up medicine for business and public service. From 1830-1832 Clark was a village trustee and in 1835 was elected Aldermen of the First Ward.
Barker, Jacob A.; Brayton, Isaac, 1805-1887.; Brayton, Nancy Burwell, 1808-1853.; Burwell, Ann Clark, 1798-1838.; Burwell, Bryant, 1796-1861.; Burwell, Dudley, 1801-1876.; Burwell, George N. (George Nathan), 1819-1891.; Burwell, Theodotus, 1805-1891.; Chappel, Robert.; Clark, John W. (John Whipple), 1799-1872.; Clark, Sally.; Clark, Sarah.; Clark, Stephen, 1772-1839.; Ellas, Frank.; Glenny, Esther Ann (Esther Ann Burwell), 1821-1897.; Glenny, Jane Grosvenor (Jane Wey Grosvenor), 1848-1898.; Glenny, William H. (William Henry), 1818-1882.; Glenny, William H. (William Henry), 1845-1929.; Lacy, John T.; Nichols, F. L.; Rathbone, Anna C. Burwell (Anna Clark Burwell), 1838-1874.; Snow, R. G. (Ruben G.), 1805-1871.; Snow, Susan Burwell, 1805-1850.; Wilgus, William J. (William John), 1865-1949; agreements; diaries; genealogies (histories); original photographs
Correspondence, primarily among family members and friends, but including some business correspondence of John W. Clark and George W. Burwell, 1824-1891; Court papers, indentures and agreements of Bryant Burwell & John W. Clark, 1831-1865; Diaries of Bryant Burwell, 1832-1847; and Correspondence and notes of Robert Stevens concerning the Burwell-Glenny family, 1951-1955.
- Correspondence, 1824 - 1891
  - Bryant and Ann Clark Burwell, 1825 - 1856
    - Letters to Ann Clark Burwell, 1824 - 1828 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Ann Clark Burwell, 1829 - 1833 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and John W. Clark, 1824 - 1830 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and John W. Clark, 1834 - 1836 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and John W. Clark, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and John W. Clark, January, 1838 - May, 1838
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and John W. Clark, June, 1838 - December, 1838
    - Bryant Burwell and John W. Clark, 1839 - 1855
    - Bryant Burwell and Dudley Burwell, 1827 - 1842
    - Bryant Burwell and Dudley Burwell, 1852 - 1856
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell and Esther Ann Burwell Glenny, 1827 - 1854
    - Bryant Burwell, Ann Clark Burwell, Susan Burwell Snow and R.G. Snow, 1831 - 1835
    - Bryant Burwell, Nancy Burwell Brayton and Isaac Brayton, 1835 - 1852
    - Bryant Burwell, George N. Burwell and Esther Ann Burwell, 1842 - 1843
    - Letters to Anna Clark Burwell, 1852 - 1855
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1824 - 1853
    - Letterbook, 1829 - 1836
- Legal and miscellaneous papers, 1826 - 1889
- Bryant Burwell diaries, 1832 - 1852
- Genealogy, 1951 - 1955